const data = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: 'What is the concept of a "space elevator"?',
    answer:
      "A space elevator is a hypothetical structure that would allow objects to be lifted from Earth's surface into space using a cable or tether. The concept involves a cable anchored to the Earth’s surface and extending to a counterweight in orbit. This would reduce the cost of launching materials into space by eliminating the need for traditional rocket propulsion.",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: 'How do rockets reach outer space?',
    answer:
      "Rockets reach outer space by using powerful engines that generate thrust to overcome Earth's gravitational pull. The rocket's engines burn fuel to propel it upward, and once it exits Earth's atmosphere, it reaches space. The force from the burning fuel (known as thrust) pushes the rocket upward until it achieves orbital velocity or escapes Earth's gravity entirely.",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question:
      'What is the concept of the "Goldilocks Zone" in relation to space exploration?',
    answer:
      'The "Goldilocks Zone," also known as the habitable zone, is the region around a star where conditions are just right for liquid water to exist on a planet\'s surface—not too hot and not too cold. This zone is important in the search for extraterrestrial life, as liquid water is considered essential for life as we know it.',
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: 'What is the biggest challenge of sending humans to Mars?',
    answer:
      'The biggest challenge of sending humans to Mars includes overcoming the vast distance (approximately 225 million kilometers), dealing with prolonged exposure to radiation, the need for reliable life support systems, and the psychological effects of long-term isolation. There are also significant challenges in landing, taking off, and returning safely from Mars.',
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: ' How long does it take to travel to Mars?',
    answer:
      'It takes about 6 to 9 months to travel to Mars using current spacecraft technology, depending on the alignment of Earth and Mars. The distance between the two planets varies as they orbit the Sun, so the length of the journey depends on the timing of the launch.',
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: 'What is the role of SpaceX’s Starship in space exploration?',
    answer:
      "SpaceX's Starship is designed to be a fully reusable spacecraft capable of carrying humans and cargo to destinations such as the Moon, Mars, and beyond. It aims to make space travel more affordable and accessible, with the long-term goal of enabling human colonization of Mars.",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: 'What are the key differences between the Moon and Mars?',
    answer:
      "While both the Moon and Mars are rocky celestial bodies, they differ in many ways\n Atmosphere: Mars has a thin atmosphere made mostly of carbon dioxide, while the Moon has no atmosphere.\n Water: Mars has evidence of ancient water and polar ice caps, whereas the Moon has water ice in permanently shadowed craters.\n Gravity: Mars has about 38% of Earth's gravity, while the Moon has only about 16.5%.",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: 'Why is the search for life on Mars important?',
    answer:
      'The search for life on Mars is crucial because it could provide insights into whether life exists or ever existed elsewhere in the universe. Mars is one of the most Earth-like planets in our solar system, and finding signs of microbial life could help scientists understand how life forms elsewhere might develop, as well as the potential for human colonization in the future.',
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: 'What is the significance of the James Webb Space Telescope?',
    answer:
      'The James Webb Space Telescope (JWST), launched in December 2021, is designed to be the successor to the Hubble Space Telescope. JWST observes the universe in infrared light, which allows it to see through dust clouds and observe distant galaxies, star formations, and exoplanets with unparalleled clarity. It is expected to make significant contributions to understanding the origins of galaxies, stars, and planets.',
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "What is the purpose of NASA's Mars Perseverance Rover?",
    answer:
      "NASA's Mars Perseverance Rover, which landed on Mars in February 2021, aims to search for signs of ancient life, collect rock and soil samples, and test new technology for future human exploration. It is also studying the planet's climate and geology to prepare for future missions.",
  },
]

export default data